# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello everyone, I am Wang Gang.
# 本期视频我给大家分享一道家常菜
Today I will share a home dish with you.
# 小炒猪肝
Stir fried pork liver.
# 首先我们准备新鲜的猪肝350克
First, let’s get 350 grams of fresh pork liver.
# 加入清水清洗干净之后备用
Clean it well with water.
# 此做法属于干香类菜需要提前清洗干净
No more cleaning is further needed.
# 清洗干净之后将猪肝切成3毫米左右的厚片
Cut it into 3mm slices.
# 同学们可以适当的切厚一些这样更方便新手操作
If you are a newbie you can slice it even thicker.
# 猪肝切好之后下一步开始腌制
Then we marinate it.
# 碗中加入食用盐小半勺（约0.5克）
0.5 gram of salt
# 加入胡椒粉0.5克
0.5 gram of white pepper
# 加入老抽3克调底色
3 grams of dark soy sauce for the color
# 调好味之后抓拌均匀备用
Hand mix the ingredients nice and well
# 最后加入少许的食用油搅拌均匀
Add some vegetable oil and stir it well
# 这一步的目的是防止猪肝下锅黏成一团
This is to prevent the pork liver from sticking together in the wok
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next we prepare the seasonings.
# 准备大蒜几颗切成小粒备用（约30克）
Cut the garlic cloves into smaller pieces (around 30 grams)
# 准备生姜1小块切成小粒备用（约15克）
Cut ginger into small pieces too (around 15 grams)
# 准备小米辣30克切碎备用
Cut red hot chili pepper finely (about 30 grams)
# 不能吃辣的同学可以不加
If you don’t like spicy food, you can skip this.
# 准备大红椒1个切成小颗粒备用
Cut the red bell pepper into small pieces.
# 准备蒜苗3根轻轻拍散之后切碎备用
Lose the garlic sprouts with the back of the knife, then cut into pieces.
# 下一步开始制作
We are now ready to cook.
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First let’s heat the wok.
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的油滑锅
Then we add some oil to coat the wok.
# 滑好锅之后将热油倒出
When the wok is well coated with oil, pour out the heated oil.
# 然后加入适量的冷油
Then add some cold oil.
# 再将腌制好的猪肝下锅滑10秒钟
Slide the pork liver in and cook it for 10 seconds
# 这一步的目的是将猪肝炒至定型（此时约5成熟）
The purpose of this step is to half cook it and firm it a little.
# 然后将切好的姜蒜粒和辣椒粒下锅翻炒30秒
Then add the ginger, garlic, and hot chili pepper, stir fry for 30 seconds
# 这一步的目的是将料头炒香
Until you smell the aroma.
# 同学们家庭小灶则需要2分钟左右
When you cook at home, it might take up to 2 minutes.
# 翻炒30秒钟之后开始调味
After 30 seconds you’ll start to add spices to it.
# 锅中加入胡椒粉0.5克
Add white pepper powder 0.5 gram
# 加入少许白糖提鲜
Then a pinch of sugar
# 加入蚝油5克
5 grams of oyster sauce
# 加入生抽酱油2克
2 grams of light soy sauce
# 最后加入老抽2克翻炒几下
Lastly, 2 grams of dark soy sauce
# 翻炒均匀之后再加入切好的蒜苗粒
Stir fry well, then add garlic sprout pieces
# 开中小火翻炒至断生即可出锅装盘
With mid-low heat, when the garlic sprout is half cooked, we can serve it.
# 一道干香下饭的小炒猪肝就制作完成
Here we have the appetizing aromatic stir fry pork liver.
# 下面开始技术总结
Next is our cooking tips:
第一， 切猪肝之前必须清洗干净，切好之后不用冲洗，
First, rinse and clean the pork liver well before cutting it. No more washing or rinsing is further needed, in order to have the best flavor.
这样才能爆出猪肝原香味（建议此做法切好之后不清洗）
第二， 腌制猪肝的时候不必加入淀粉，只需要盐胡椒粉老抽即可
Second, no need for any corn starch. Only need salt, white pepper powder, and dark soy sauce.
第三， 此版本为家常做法，湖南地区可以加入适量的豆豉增加地方风味
Third, you can add fermented soybean if you prefer HuNan cuisine.
小炒猪肝的技术总结完毕
That concludes the tips for Stir-Fried Pork Liver.